Hi this is Zephyr Clarke-Dolberg with Miami Dog Training in Miami, Florida.
In this clip we're going to talk about how to teach your dog not to run away.
First thing you really want to pay attention to is the leash.
This is your number one tool for being in control so the first rule about letting your dog not letting your dog run away is control and opportunity.
If they don't have the opportunity to run away they're not going to do it.
You know as far as training goes in the beginning we start with a five to six foot leash.
I prefer a five cause it's less material to have to work with.
But just the same all the training first starts with the leash.
If you can't get the dog to do something on the leash how are you going to get him to do something off the leash or for that matter if you drop the leash?
So one of the biggest things is teaching the dog to stay.
We tell him to stay.
Once the dog is taught to stay you don't have to worry about him running away.
You can drop the leash as long as the dog is obedience trained that's a big major part.
My name is Zephyr Clarke-Dolberg and this is Miami Dog Training.